If we forget the premium of this plan for some time, then HDFC ERGO Optima secure
is one of the Best Selling Plans in India. With strong parentage of HDFC Bank Ltd and
good claim settlement metrics gives even more strength to this plan.
But recently launched Health plans are very flexible. Now HDFC ERGO has come up with 3 latest riders in which it
is also offering you the facility of first time maternity. In today's video, we
will understand the USP of HDFC Ergo Optima Secure, i.e. the features which
make this plan very special. We will know about the three riders, what
coverage will the riders give us, what are the terms and conditions applicable on them and
for how much rupees we will get them. Along with this, we will also You will also understand whether HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure Plan gives you coverage of modern treatments. Today's video
is going to be the latest review video of HDFCC Ergo Optima Secure Plan in which we
will see this plan with all three riders. We will understand what it looks like. So if you
want to understand this plan in an unbiased and transparent manner then
you must watch today's video and I will try not to take too much of your time
but we will We will also take care that there is no compromise with the quality of information,
so let's start this video without any delay. The
first USP of this plan and the most special feature is Secure  Benefit and
this plan has also been named after this benefit. Secure Benefit says that as much as your sum
is insured, you get an extra amount equal to the amount of rupees for which you have purchased the policy,
other than the base sum insured from the First Day: If my
policy is of Rs 20 lakh, then my policy from the first day itself is ₹ 20 lakh secured benefit
which I can use during any claim. Next benefit comes plus
benefit. in this benefit we get 50% of the basic sum insured amount every year till
maximum 100% of sum insured. Today my policy is of ₹ 20 lakh, on the first renewal
I will get ₹ 10 lakh plus benefit . On the next renewal, I will again
get ₹ 10 lakh plus benefit and when my plus benefit becomes equal to my sum insured i.e.
policy of ₹ 20 lakh and plus benefit of ₹ 20 lakh, then this is its maximum limit.
Next benefit comes Protect Benefit. Protect Benefit
gives us coverage of non-medical i.e. consumable items under this plan, so this benefit insures
that when a claim comes, the non-medical items. No deduction should be made from our claim amount
and the fourth USP of Optima Secure Plan is the restore benefit. The company says that when your
basic sum is used in the insured treatment, then once in a year up to 100% of
the sum insured, your amount will be restored.
On the basis of these four benefits, the company says that if you renew this plan Optima Secure Plan for 3 consecutive years,
then your basic sum will be increased. You
can avail four times the coverage of the sum insured from the first claim and how much truth is there in this claim. We have also
discussed in our previous review video. If we talk about sum insured, then
under Optima Secure Plan , you can avail minimum sum insured ranging from ₹ 5 lakh to maximum ₹
2 crore of sum insured. Pre and post hospitalization expenses,
60 days of pre hospitalization expenses and 180 days of pre-hospitalization expenses. Days of post hospitalization
expenses will be covered in this plan. The limit of air ambulance expenses is ₹ 5 lakh
and within this plan you also get the option of annual deductible through which you
can reduce your premium. Even before the launch of these three new riders,
there were some minor changes in this plan such as
the capping of maximum entry age for adults was removed, now the maximum entry There is no capping on the age and the
moratorium period is also 5 years as per the latest guidelines of IRDA.
If we talk about the waiting period, then the initial waiting period is 30 days i.e.
within the first 30 days, no other treatment other than accidental treatment
will be covered by this plan. The specific diseases or the listed ailments will be covered by you
after 24 months. And if there is any pre-existing disease, then its coverage
will be covered by this plan after 36 months i.e. 3 years. Before this, let us mention three new add-ons of this plan
Let's understand the existing addons of this plan.
First Addon is My Health Critical Illness. This Addon covers 51 critical illness means there
are 51 serious diseases. If any of these is diagnosed, then
the insurance company gives you the sum benefit because this is a benefit based feature.
You get a fixed compensation from the company. The next add-on is hospital cash
for any number of days. The policy holder remains admitted in the hospital but to get day compensation
other than treatment cost, you can take this addon.
You already know the rider of Optima Well Being which gives you coverage of OPD expenses but
for that you will have to take addon in your policy. Apart from this, there
is Individual Personal Accident Rider i.e. which after a personal accident, if there is any disability or
In case of death of an adult policy holder, you get that coverage through this rider
and the final and most important addon which is Unlimited Restoration benefit
In standard plan, how many times can you have in the whole year,
it can be once in a year till 100% of sum ish but if you
have taken this rider with unlimited restoration benefit, then this limit will be removed and
your amount will be restored for unlimited times. Now we will discuss all three new riders
First addon is Parenthood, you get maternity covered in it means delivery charges will be covered by insurer
and also some other covers related to maternity are covered.
You can take this rider with both Optima Secure and Optima Restore plans.
First of all, let's talk about the sum of how much maternity
coverage you will get, then those four options are 50k ₹ 1 lakh 1.5 lakh and ₹ 2 lakh of
delivery charges can be covered in this addon. Once we understand in detail what will be covered,
then if we talk about the number of deliveries, then inside this addon there are two normal
or C. Section Deliveries: You can cover both the deliveries together and this
is the limit for two deliveries, which also includes doctor recommended medical termination. If a
Blessed policy holder delivers twins, then only one delivery event
will be counted. If we talk about pre and post natal expenses, then both
the expenses will be covered for 180 days i.e. 180 days before the delivery
and 180 days post delivery. Natal expenses will
be covered. What all are the expenses, you are currently visible on the screen. IVF
procedures can also be covered under Parent Hood addon.
You can cover it only for the first and second cycle of treatment in life time. Rest of
the conditions are visible to you on the screen. Not only this, along with this, you
can also get coverage of Embryo Freezing in Parent Hood addon. Now friends, let's talk about something
very important. The first condition that we should know about this addon
is that you cannot take the rider separately. You
can also club this rider with any base policy, which
is the product which I mentioned is Optima Secure or Optima Restore. Along with these, you can take a parent hood rider. To take this rider,
any female member above the policy should be minimum 18 years of age
and This rider is not available for policy holders below 18 years of age.
The sum insured of the parent hood, which is the four options mentioned by me,
is independent of your basic sum insured. If any claim comes tomorrow related to the coverage of the parent hood rider,
then you will have to take it from the same sum insured which is the coverage I have told you and
this amount of this claim will not have any effect on your basic sum insured. Now
let us know once what are the things which are not covered under the Parent Hood Rider.
First of all, you will get this claim only if the insurance company
accepts your Parent Hood claim, accepts the maternity claim, the waiting period for
claim of this Parent Hood addon is 24 months and the most important thing that I saw here is that
even after taking the Parent Hood rider, the coverage of the new born baby is not there. Now let 's
understand the pricing of parent hood once,
how much rupees you will have to pay for how much coverage, I told you four options - 50000, ₹1 lakh
1.5 lakh and ₹ 2  lakh, if you want sum inshore of parent hood then you will get it around ₹ 14000 plus
GST approximate , that is, this amount will be added to the premium of your policy,
if we talk about parent coverage of ₹ 1 lakh. You
will get that in Rs 26600 ps GST If we talk about 1.5 lakh off coverage then it will cost
38220 plus GST and if we want to take coverage off
Now comes the nest addon Limitless, you can easily guess that some limit is being removed
and that is your limit of sum insured during any treatment.
If your sum insured is below 50 lakh in Optima Secure plan is ₹ lakh then
you can stretch any claim up to unlimited amount once in the entire life time
if you have taken this add on. Limitless and if your sum insured is Rs 50 lakh and above
, then you can make two life time claims so that you
can stretch their limit till unlimited amount. Now we have known what benefit
we will get through Limitless but let us see some conditions which are very important to understand.
The first condition is that you
will get this separately along with the same Optima Secure and Optima Restore plans. You cannot take this as a single rider. The second
condition is that you can use it only within the Indian geographical limits.
The third condition says that this is an indemnity based benefit, that is,
you will get compensation as much as you spend on your treatment. Unlimited
does not mean that you will get unlimited amount of money as much as will be spent on treatment.
You will get the same amount of claim, only there will be no limit that your sum insured
gets exhausted. It can be used in three categories of treatments. The
first is inpatient hospitalization i.e. if any policy holder gets admitted and
takes any treatment, then it can be used for that. Second is day
care treatments. Those procedures for which
it is not necessary to be admitted. Due to technical advancement, these surgeries are done in two-four hours, so their
You can also use them for And third coverage is for inpatient Ayush treatment
. You can also use Limitless addon for alternative treatments.
How will it be used? Suppose, I have purchased the policy and a claim has come and I have to
activate this limitless rider under this claim, so
what do I have to do? I have to send an email directly to the insurance company
before hospitalization, during hospitalization or after discharge. Within 30 days,
I can tell the insurance company through email that I
want to make this claim limitless, then the insurance company will review your claim and
give you its approval. What will be the sequence of the sum insured that will be used during today,
then when your basic sum insured, secure benefit plus benefit, restoration
benefit, every type of sum insured gets exhausted, after that the sum of limitless will be used.
There will be no limit on the sum insured till the limit of indemnity i.e. till the time you
need money for the treatment of
this claim , but keep in mind that limitless benefit will be triggered after use of all sum insured.
the frequency of limitless is according to your sum insured i.e. you can use limitless once in life time
or twice if that limit is reached,
you use it, after that this benefit will automatically deactivate. The final condition will be done.
It says that when you opt limitless addons, all existing conditions like co-payment, sub limits will remain the same
Limitless addon will have no impact on them
the turn to check the price of limitless. For how many rupees
will this limitless rider be added to your plan? Here, the company has given the option of Sum Insured in the left side table.
How much is your policy, i.e. how much is the coverage? Then
after that, in the first row, it is told that if it
is taken with domestic plans, that is, it is taken only with those plans which will give you coverage in India.
So , how to see this: Suppose I have only Optima Secure plan
and my base sum insured is of ₹ 20 lakh, then my loading
percentage is 5 % . Now for a coverage of ₹ 20 lakh, suppose my premium comes
from ₹ 40000, then its loading of  5% will be added to it, that is, the amount of
my premium will be added to the base policy of the standard policy. If I have
a limitless rider in it, then If you want to add, then the mentioned loading percentage amount
will be calculated by multiplying it with the net premium of my base policy and
that percentage will be added inside that policy with respect to my sum insured.
Apart from this, in the second row, the company says that if you take this add on
with the Secure Global plan, then this percentage which is the amount of your total premium
will be added to your premium and if you take it with Optima Secure Global. If you take it inside the Plus plan,
then the percentage of loading mentioned in the third row is that of the total net
premium. This percentage of the net premium of the base plan will be added to it for limitless.
Third add on comes. Friends, you already know the full form of A B C D,
Asthma, B BP, Cholesterol and Diabetes. The coverage of these four
is also in your base policy, but what is special through this rider is that there is a waiting period for you
to cover them under one policy. If it is PED, then you can prepon it,
you can take their coverage from 31 days, that is, if you have taken rider A B C D, after that,
after 30 days, from 31st day, you can take its coverage in your policy.
If there is any medical complication related to these four, then it
will cover your policy. The special thing is that this rider
is not restricted to both these plans. You can club it
with the insurance plan. Once you have taken AB CD On and added it to your policy
, it cannot be removed later. When can you take it? You
can also take the time of taking a fresh policy and even when you renew your policy, AB CD
rider can be added. Now suppose there are four members in my policy
but only one member needs to use AB CD rider, then you
For selected members also, they can choose ABCD rider, who
have such problems and they can take claim related to it. You will
have to pay the premium only for those members. Now the question comes that for how many years will we have to pay the premium for the ABCD rider,
i.e. once we have added it, the amount will be charged for only one year or if it
is for 3 years, suppose it is PED, then its waiting period was 3 years, we reduced it to 31.
If it becomes one day, will it have to be paid for 3 years or for life time? Whenever
the policy is renewed, its money will be added. So, the answer is that
you will have to pay it every year along with the premium. There is no limit of 1 year or 3 years. Now
because it is not possible to remove this rider in this policy, as long as the policy
runs, its premium will be added to your policy. So,
we understood all these three new riders today till the first week of. March These riders
have been introduced by the insurance company but they are not yet applicable i.e.
the company has not yet started offering them to you with the new policy. They have only been introduced
but within a few days you will also be offered these d'ons. You
can add them to your policy. Now before I tell you my opinion about this plan,
let me tell you the pros and cons. What has changed in this plan even after this add on
? Same everything remains the same, before that a final question comes, will
there be coverage of modern treatments under HDFC Ergo Optima Secure plan?
This question is asked many times. Even in the comment section and in the previous review video, we
were not able to discuss it. So the answer is that
there is still no mention of modern treatments anywhere in the policy words of HDFC Ergo Optima Secure. So
what does it mean that if my treatment ever includes modern treatments? Treatments
have to be used and if there is a need for them then the company will not give me a claim. If
the insurance company wants, they can refuse you and
can also approve your claim if they want, but will it be right if they refuse?
If we talk about the guidelines of IRDA, then they have strictly said that the listed 12
are modern treatments and apart from this, if there are any modern treatments, then the insurance companies
should provide coverage for them. This will happen provided it should be a part of the treatment, this means that
if your doctor says that it is medically necessary to use this modern treatment then
the insurance company cannot refuse your claim. Yes they can but you
can challenge it on the basis of IRDA guidelines because
I cannot tell whether the insurance company will approve it or not but still you can contest their
claim rejection if any such If this scenario happens and I feel
that if the insurance company does not provide coverage of modern treatments then they
should be included in the exclusion. If they have to provide coverage then they
should be mentioned in the policy earnings like other policies are being done by other companies.
What is the problem in this? Keeping it in a confused state
causes a lot of trouble to the policy holders. Now friends, the final section comes.
Let us discuss the pros and cons of HDFC ERGO Optima Secure. The first drawback which was already going on is
regarding the pricing i.e. HDFC ERGO Optima Secure is already so expensive, now these
riders are also very costly. If suppose I
take Parent Hood Rider under my Optima Secure base plan and take a coverage of ₹ 50000, then annually
I will have to pay ₹ 17000 for it. There is a waiting period of 2 years, so ₹ 50000.
I am already paying Rs 17,000 for maternity coverage and will have to pay this for 2 years, so the debt
amounts will be Rs 34,000 and if there is no delivery claim in 2 years, then
including the cost of the third year, it will be Rs 51,000. So I don't think this is a good risk to reward ratio,
so I found the pricing of this addon quite expensive. Now let us see
if you are taking an expensive policy. Riders will also be expensive, no problem, I have a lot of money,
the money is not going to run out, but still there is no coverage even on newborn in it.
Now suppose there is a delivery, we cover the cost of delivery.
During any delivery, who has the maximum risk, either, mother or child, but newborn baby
coverage is not there in it, which is a major drawback. Talking about the limitless addon,
it is okay, I found it to be fine, but there is a difference in it too, if you have the same.
If the sum insured is higher,  say ₹ 20 lakh, the loading is only 5% , that is, the more
your sum insured, the cheaper the cost effective you will get as a limitless rider.
If we talk about AB CD rider, then it is available for every plan and it
can also be good for those policy holders who already
have such conditions, but here also the cost matters a lot, so friends, we have understood HDFC
ergo Optima Secure Plan. How did you like this plan with the riders, what are the good
things and what are the shortcomings? Because I have told you my opinion, you
can also tell your opinion in the comment section. If you liked the video information, then
do like the video to show your love and support.
Do share the video wherever necessary because sending this information to someone else through your one share
can help them too and
if you want to get similar unbiased transparent information videos in the future, then do subscribe to the channel. Is HDFC
ergO as a health insurance company better than other competitors or not? If
you want to compare this, then you should REFER the report card series. You must watch it once,
you will be able to understand the insurance company in a better way, I am Harvinder
Singh, now I take permission from you, I will meet you in the next video, till then
take care of yourself, be happy and stay healthy, Jai Hind.